# Kristen Hazard

### Developer

kristen@hazardbio.com

# Summary

I meandered my way to my programming career. I started out as a Mechanical Engineer but I never really understood the mechanical parts of Mechanical Engineering. I then gravitated toward Law School which I really enjoyed. While awaiting my Bar Exam results (which I passed) I picked up a programming job during the hey day of Bubble 2.0. To my surprise I really loved it and I've been programming every since. It's been about 10 years now.

I'm really good at working in the analyst/programmer role. I am able to communicate with clients and management to gather requirements and I can successfully implement those requirements as applications. I like working in small teams. I like to develop in small iterations for fast feedback from the client to keep me on track.

I'd like to continue building web applications on the Ruby on Rails framework. I'd like to help companies implement small to medium sized applications.

# **Specialties**

Languages: Ruby, C#, .NET, SQL, XML, XSLT, VB, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Databases: SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, Sqlite

OS: Mac, Windows, Linux

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, .NET

# Experience

## Founder Designer Developer at Suntoucher Software

April 2009 - Present (5 months)

Creating web applications on Ruby on Rails framework.

## Vice President Information Technology at Strategic Merchandising Partners

April 2004 - April 2009 (5 years 1 month)

Designed, developed, tested and implemented solutions using agile processes in .NET environment (C# and SQL Server).

Gathered requirements based on discussions with users and management.

Was responsible for architecture of all solutions developed.

Built and managed a small IT department during a time of extreme growth in business.

Mentored junior members of IT department.

#### **Software Engineer at Quovadx**

January 1999 - April 2004 (5 years 4 months)

Managed large teams of developers in California and Bangalore to successfully implement custom healthcare workflow solutions on proprietary platform. Developed applications on platform similar to ASP using XML, XSLT, JavaScript and SQL. Managed installation and implementation of custom software solutions at client site.

1 recommendation available upon request

#### Software Engineer at Confer Software, Inc.

January 1999 - December 2002 (4 years)

See above.

### Education

### **New College of California**

J.D., Law, 1996 - 1998

**Activities and Societies:** Faculty and Curriculum Development Committee Member 1996-1997, Teaching Assistant Criminal Procedure January 1997-May 1997

#### California Polytechnic State University-San Luis Obispo

B.S., Mechanical Engineering, 1989 - 1993

Activities and Societies: Society of Women Engineers Co-Director Team Technical Project

## Honors and Awards

Outstanding Woman in Engineering, 1992
Wilson Scholar Athlete, 1989
Driscoll Truit Academic Award, 1989
Most Valuable Player, Hancock College Volleyball Team, 1988

### Interests

Yoga, Hiking, Music

# Kristen Hazard

## Developer

kristen@hazardbio.com



# 1 person has recommended Kristen

"Kristen was our most trusted IT consultant. Whenever possible, those of us in the eastern region, lobbied for her to come out to work with our clients on their system modifications. She is hard-working, intuitive, and enthusiastic. Our client contacts at a publicly-traded nursing home chain and a Blue Cross Blue Shield plan all raved about Kristen."

— Warren Demurjian, Sales Director, Eastern Region, Confer Software, worked with Kristen at Quovadx

Contact Kristen on LinkedIn